Guide to the Cornell University News Service records, [ca. 1920s-2000s].
Cornell University News Service records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University News Service records, [ca. 1920s-2000s].
4-3-15
Cornell University. News Service.
250 cubic feet. 2265 tape recordings.
Photographs, Printed material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, news press releases, notes, publicity material, newspaper clippings, distribution lists, administrative files, photographs, biographies, and other records of events at Cornell.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cornell University News Service was formerly known as the Office of Public Relations, Public Relations and Information, and the News Bureau. It currently reports to the Vice President for University Relations.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, news press releases, notes, publicity material, newspaper clippings, distribution lists, administrative files, photographs, biographies, and other records of events at Cornell such as an Andrew Dickson White Commemorative Service, 1957; Cornell University Dinners; communism at Cornell; Olin Library Dedication, 1962; visit of Vice President Richard M. Nixon, 1956; installation of Cornell President Deane Waldo Malott; Festival of Contemporary Arts, 1950-1959; School of Industrial and Labor Relations dedication; Cornell Latin American Year, 1965-1966; International Student Conference, 1965; Cornell's centennial; and other events. Typescript and mimeographed press releases concerning faculty, students, and events at Cornell University. Audiotapes of radio programs and campus events, radio productions, movie films, and other records.
Photographs used by News Service and in Publications in the normal course of their operations. Contains photographs used by News Service throughout its history, spanning a wide range of subjects, which includes buildings, people, events, student activities, and other Cornell-relation miscellany.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Malott, Deane Waldo, 1898-; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Cornell University -- Anniversaries, etc.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University -- Presidents.; Cornell University; Cornell University -- Public relations.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University. News Bureau.; Cornell University. University Relations.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Includes collections 8-1-15, 4-3-111, 8-2-350, 8-2-565, 4-3-885, 8-2-885, 4-3-922, 8-1-1186, 8-1-1321, 8-1-1699.
Photographic assignments done by Jill Peltzman are located in 4-3-15 Box 63.
See also Cornell University Relations and Public Information Office audio visual records collection #4-3-875: http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA00875.
See also Cornell Clippings File, #13-8-3367: http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA03367.
See also Cornell University Council records collection #8-2-1359 for public information office records pertaining to the Council and information pertaining to special campus events attended by members, such as dedications.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Press releases and News Service records 1930s-1950s
Collection #4-3-111 boxes 1-8
Series II. Press releases 1940s-1970s
Collection #4-3-885 boxes 1-9, 11-15. Box 10 is believed lost at the Annex
Series III. Office of Public Information records, 1940s-1960s
Collection #8-1-1186 boxes 1-2
Series IV. News Bureau records, 1950s-1960s
Collection #8-1-1321 box 1
Series V. Office of Public Information news files, 1920s-1970s
Collection #8-1-1699 boxes 1-6
Series VI. Cornell University News Services records, 1920s-2000s
Collection #8-1-15 boxes and volumes 0-22 and superseded by #4-3-15 boxes 23-152. Boxes 99-114 are part of an addition from the Cornell Chronicle that then continues with boxes 133-152.
Subseries VIa. Press Releases, News Clippings, Distribution Lists, Administrative Files, Subject Files
General
Alpha Subject File, Mostly 1970s
Alpha Subject File, Mostly 1980s
Alpha Subject File, 1990s-2000s
Cornell Bylaws and Board of Trustees Press Releases
Lectures
Fellowships
Cornell Faculty and Staff Biographies and Curriculum Vitae 1960s-1970s
The Cornell Tradition
Clippings and Press Releases by Individual, last name
General
Alumni Subject File
Trustee Subject File
Faculty Subject Files
Subseries VIb. Photographs
Athletics and Physical Education
Buildings (Interior and Exterior)
Classes, Programs, and Student Activities
People
People by Category
Individuals by Last Name
Events
Miscellaneous
Outdoor Locations
Science (Research, Labs, and Experiments)
Series VII. Cornell University News Service records, Audio and Visual Material
Includes, but not exclusively, collection #4-3-885 Tapes
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Press releases and News Service records, collection #4-3-111, 1930s-1950s
  - Press Releases, Pre-July, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, August, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, September, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, October, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, November, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, December, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, January, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, February, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, March, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, April, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, May, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, June, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, August, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Press Releases, September, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, October, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Press Releases, November, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Press Releases, December, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 21)
    Correspondence, Men's and Women's Club Rosters, Board of Trustee press releases and information, List of Foreign Students and geographic distribution, miscellaneous press releases
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 22)
    Contains pamphlets, Summer Student Employee applications and photographs, press releases
  - ROTC Press Releases, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 1, Folder 23)
  - College of Agriculture Press Releases (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Press Releases, January, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Press Releases, February, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Press Releases, March, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Press Releases, April, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Press Releases, May, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 11-12)
  - Press Releases, June, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, July, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, August, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, September, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, October, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, November, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, December, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, January, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Press Releases, February, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Press Releases, March, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, April, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Press Releases, May, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Press Releases, June, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, July, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, August, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, September, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, October, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Press Releases, November, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases, December, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, January, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, February, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 17-18)
  - Press Releases, March, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 3, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, April, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Press Releases, May, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases, June, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Press Releases, July, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Press Releases, August, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Press Releases, September, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, October, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 12-13)
  - Press Releases, November, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Press Releases, December, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Press Releases, January, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Press Releases, February, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Press Releases, March, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Press Releases, April, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Press Releases, May, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Press Releases, June, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Press Releases, July, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Press Releases, August, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Press Releases, September, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Press Releases, October, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Press Releases, November, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Press Releases, December, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 17-18)
  - Press Releases, January, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Press Releases, February, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 21-22)
  - Press Releases, March, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 23-24)
  - Press Releases, April, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 5, Folder 25-26)
  - Press Releases, May, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Press Releases, June, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Press Releases, July, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Press Releases, August, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, September, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Press Releases, October, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 10)
  - Arthur Stanton Adams Information, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, Photographs, some Member Information, Press Releases
  - Cornell's 80th Anniversary, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 13-14)
    Press Releases, Pamphlets, Correspondence
  - Survey of Athletic Conditions, January-July, 1929 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 15)
  - Press Related Correspondence, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Professor of Physics, Frederick Bedell, and his "Deaf Speaker" (hearing aid) "Deaf Speaker", 194? (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 17)
    Photographs and News Article
  - Cornell's Shelter for Observers, 1931 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 17 A)
    Photographs and News Article on astronomical observation shelter
  - Industrial and Labor Relations, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 18)
    Correspondence, Press Releases, and Pamphlets on Bernay's Lecture Series
  - Cornell Football, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 19)
    Correspondence, Articles, Magazine on Cornell Football
  - Ornithology, 1933-1945 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 20)
    Articles, Reprints from "The Auk", Arthur A. Allen's publications
  - Howard Blakeslee, 1933-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 21)
    Various articles written by Howard W. Blakeslee, Associated Press Science Editor. Includes photos (7) of Dr. Phillips Thomas, Westinghouse Research Engineer, and associated articles (1937)
  - American College Public Relations Association, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 22)
    Correspondence, Articles; program of its District II Annual Meeting, January 1942 at Willard Straight Hall
  - Student Association of the School of Business and Public Administration, 1949-1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 23)
    Correspondence, Balance Sheet Publications
  - Louis C. Boochever, 1940 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 24)
    Articles Written by Boochever, regarding Big Red Team
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 25)
  - President Celal Bayar, of Turkey, 1954 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 26)
    Articles, Correspondence, and notes regarding President Bayar of Turkey and his projected visit
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory Reports, 1949-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 27)
    Report: Application of Continues Wave Radar in a Possible Solution to the Problem of Collision Prevention in Flight
    Report: Annual Report to Board of Directors
    Report: Variable Density Wind Tunnel
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 28)
  - Louis C. Boochever, 1930's (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 29)
    Correspondence, reports on major Cornell buildings, including Plant Science, Martha Van Rensselaer, Warren, Myron Taylor, War Memorial
  - John Burton, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 30)
    Articles pertaining to John Burton, Vice President of Cornell
  - Academic Freedom, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 31)
    Articles, pamphlets, correspondence
  - Greater Cornell Fund, 1948-1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 32)
    Press Releases, Brochures
  - Greater Cornell Fund Film, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 33)
    Information on the Greater Cornell Fund Films
  - Cornellian Council, 1931 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 34)
    Correspondence, Brochure
  - Edmund Ezra Day, 1946-1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 35)
    Correspondence, including 2 letters to Day protesting the June 19, 1949 interracial marriage of Paul Robeson, Jr., '49 and Marilyn Paula Greenberg, '48; also biographical material on President Day
  - Edmund Ezra Day Inauguration, 1937 (Box 4-3-111 - 6, Folder 36)
    Inauguration Information
  - Press-Radio Dinner, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 1)
  - Charles Love Durham, 1940 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 2)
    Biography, Press Release, Photograph
  - Endowment, 1919,1930 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 3)
    Addresses at Cornell Council Roll Call 1930, Cornell University Semi-Centennial Endowment
  - Inauguration of Livingston Farrand, 1921 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Films, 1949-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, Press Releases
  - War Effort Films, 1942 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 6)
    Correspondence, Movie Information, Office of War Information
  - Founder's Day, 1932 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 6 A)
  - Fraternities, 1949-1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 7)
    Articles, Fraternity Periodicals, Correspondence, Directories
  - Greek Life, 1930 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 8)
    Correspondence
  - Joseph L. Green, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 9)
  - Floyd Richtmyer (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 10)
    Press Release
  - Floyd K. Graham (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 11)
  - Heckscher Research Council (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Life, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 13)
    Newspaper Clippings, Articles
  - Cornell Ranking (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 14)
    Article
  - Cornell at War, 1929, 1941 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 15)
    List of Enlisted Men, Press Releases, Deceased Alumni
  - Cornell Founding Information Press Releases, 1930-1940 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Housing Press Releases, 1946-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 17)
  - Raymond F. Howes, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 18)
    Press Releases, Photograph
  - Biological Sciences, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 19)
    Newspaper articles, Bulletins, Correspondence, Press Releases
  - Cornell Interfraternity Alumni Association, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 20-21)
    Report on Distribution, Mailing List, Correspondence
  - Interfraternity Council, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 22)
    Pamphlets, Council Member List, Correspondence
  - Ivy League Relations, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 23)
    Newspaper Articles, Bulletins, Correspondence, Frank Bowles, Photograph
  - Hearing Experiments, 1941 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 24)
    Press Releases, Correspondence
  - Vladimir Karapetoff, 1932-1933 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 25)
  - Alva Kelly, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 26)
    Photograph, Correspondence
  - Dexter Kimball, 1945 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 27)
    Biography Press Release
  - William Julian King Press Release (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 28 A)
    Photograph of Cornell Summer Program for Teachers on Latin America, Dean Rusk, Correspondence
  - Library Press Release, 1934 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 29)
  - Deane Waldo Mallott, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 30)
    Correspondence, Press Releases, Newspaper Articles
  - The Tinkham Unit Memorial Service, 1942 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 31)
    Speeches, Programs, Press Releases
  - Emmet J Murphy, 1940 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 32)
    Article with Photograph, Press Releases
  - Floyd Newman Laboratory of Nuclear Sciences, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 33)
    Articles, Programs, Correspondence, Press Releases
  - Albert W. Smith (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 34)
    Press Release, Copies of Etchings, Photograph
  - Nobel Prize Dinner, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 35)
    Press Releases, Information on Cornell Nobel Prize winners
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Day, 1935 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 37)
    Press Releases and Correspondence
  - Class of 1913, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 38)
    Correspondence to Cornell alumni Fund Council
  - American College Public Relations Competition, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 39)
  - Office Report Statistics, 1942-1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 40-41)
    Press Releases, Reports
  - Intensive Study of Contemporary Russian Civilization, 1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 42)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, Pamphlets
  - Campus Salute, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 43)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, Speeches
  - Livingston Farrand Letters, 1935-1936 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 44)
    Correspondence with Secretary Woodford Patterson and Winthrop Kent Esq.
  - Nutritional Sciences, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 45)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, Savage Hall
  - Savage Hall Dedication, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 46-47)
  - Donald J. Shank, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 48)
    Press Release, Photograph
  - South Hill Faculty Housing Report, 1946 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 49)
    Report for the Board of Trustees, with Photographs
  - Nutritional Sciences, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 7, Folder 45)
  - Forum on Functions of Modern Diversity, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Administration, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 2)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, Pamphlets on New Hotel
  - Statler Hotel, 1948-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Hotel Ezra Cornell, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, Programs
  - Statler Hotel, 1941-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 6)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, pamphlets, Journal Articles, Copy of Floor Plans
  - Cornell Employee Strike, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 7, 9)
    Press Releases, Correspondence, Notes
  - Foreign Student Admissions, 1950-1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, Admission information
  - Whitman Daniels, 1949 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 10)
    Various Correspondence
  - Youth Assemblies, 1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 11)
    National Youth Assembly, Young Adult Council: Pamphlets, Correspondence, Press Releases
  - Veterinary College, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 12)
    Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - War Memorial Dedication, 1931 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 13-14)
    Correspondence, Pamphlets, Press Release
  - Founders Day, 1931 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 15)
    Founders Day Speech
  - Andrew Dickson White, 1915, 1932 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 16)
    Miscellaneous Correspondence (1915), Celebrating AD White (1932)
  - Enlisted University Staff, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 17)
    Surveys, Correspondence, Bulletins
  - The Greater Cornell Committee, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 17 A)
    Speeches
  - Inauguration of the Greater Cornell Fund, 1948 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 18-21)
  - Civil Liberty Lecture Series, 1944 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 22)
    Lectures and Speeches, Press Releases
  - Veterinary Survey, 1945 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 23)
  - Ross Marvin, 1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 24)
    Correspondence, Press Releases, Photographs pertaining to the naming of the Ross Marvin Liberty Ship
  - Enrollment, 1945 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 25)
    Correspondence regarding returning Veterans and overcrowded colleges, Articles
  - Fraternity Percentages, 1934-1937 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 26)
    Correspondence on the percentage of students in social organizations and fraternities
  - Cornell Articles, 1922, 1940 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 27)
    Article, Correspondence pertaining to an article, "The Blast", about Cornell
  - Karl Dallenbach Experiment (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 28)
    Correspondence, Press Release, Photograph copies pertaining to Karl Dallenbach's experiment on the "sixth sense" in the blind
  - Army/Navy Semesters (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 29)
    Press Releases on the new semester dates and withdrawal for service information
  - Student War Effort, 1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 30)
    Press Releases pertaining to events held by student organizations to raise money for the war
  - Shell-Shock Study, 1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 31)
    Press Release on the study of shell-shock in human beings, using gun-shy dogs
  - Dorothy M Cothran, 1942-1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 32)
    Press Release, Transcript, and Photograph from Dorothy Cothran's appearance and representation of Cornell on the Fred Allen broadcast
  - Workshop on Latin America, the Far East, and the British Coommonwealth of the Nations, 1942 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 33)
    Report and photographs
  - Miscellaneous Press Releases, 1943 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 34)
  - Wordsworth Collection, 1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 35)
    Correspondence, flier, press releases, list of photographs from the collection
  - 4th Annual Management Conference, School of Business and Public Administration, 1952 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 35 A)
    Program, Speakers
  - Miscellaneous Press releases, 1946-1950 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 36, 37, 41)
    Statler hotel, Greater Cornell Fund, Animal and Human Virus transmission, Endowments, Sports
  - Commencements and Reunions, 1948-1951 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 38, 42)
    Programs, Notes, Press Releases
  - New Cooperative Law Course Press Release, 1947 (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 39)
  - Sage Chapel Choir (Box 4-3-111 - 8, Folder 40)
    Press Release pertaining to the choir singing on the radio
- Series II. Press releases, collection #4-3-885, 1940s-1970s
  - Press Releases, July-December 1947 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 1)
  - Press Releases, January- June 1948 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 2)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1948 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 3)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1949 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 4)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1949 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 5)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1950 (Box 4-3-885 - 1, Volume 6)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1950 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Volume 1)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1951 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Volume 2)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1951 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Volume 3)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1952 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Volume 4)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1952 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Volume 5)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1953 (Box 4-3-885 - 2, Folder 6-8)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1953 (Box 4-3-885 - 3, Volume 1)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1954 (Box 4-3-885 - 3, Volume 2)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1954 (Box 4-3-885 - 3, Volume 3)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1955 (Box 4-3-885 - 3, Volume 4)
  - Press Releases, July-December 1955 (Box 4-3-885 - 3, Volume 5)
  - Press Releases, January-June 1956 (Box 4-3-885 - 4, Volume 1)